Welcome
to
Arxflix.
Today,
we're
exploring
Seed
Prover,
a
groundbreaking
approach
to
automated
theorem
proving.
This
system
combines
deep
and
broad
reasoning
to
tackle
complex
mathematical
problems.
Traditional
methods
struggle
with
theorem
proving
due
to
the
lack
of
clear
supervision
signals.
Seed
Prover
addresses
this
by
using
Lean,
a
domain
-specific
language
that
provides
formal
verification
of
proofs.
Seed
Prover
employs
a
lemma
-style
whole
proof
reasoning
model.
It
iteratively
refines
proofs
based
on
lean
feedback,
proved
lemmas,
and
self
-summarization.
To
solve
IMO
-level
contest
problems,
Seed
Prover
uses
three
test
-time
inference
strategies.
These
strategies
enable
both
deep
and
broad
reasoning,
allowing
the
system
to
explore
various
problem
-solving
paths.
This
figure
illustrates
the
growth
in
many
F2F
test
performance
over
time,
showcasing
Seed
Prover's
significant
advancements
compared
to
previous
models.
Recognizing
the
limitations
of
lean
in
geometry,
the
researchers
developed
CGometry.
This
geometry
reasoning
engine
outperforms
previous
formal
geometry
engines.
Seed
geometry
uses
forward
-chaining
to
derive
all
known
facts
by
checking
applicable
rules.
It
identifies
the
minimum
dependency
relations
in
a
geometry
problem's
configuration.
The
system
also
performs
extensive
search
in
the
geometry
space,
establishing
unique
geometry
problems
requiring
auxiliaries.
A
seed
model
trained
on
this
data
becomes
an
effective
neurosymbolic
geometry
prover,
Seed
Prover
distinguishes
itself
through
several
key
features.
These
include
lemma
-style
proving,
iterative
proof
refinement,
and
test
-time
scaling.
Lemma
-style
proving
allows
clear
identification
of
proved
and
unproved
lemmas.
Lemmas
are
modular
and
can
be
combined
freely.
Iterative
proof
refinement
uses
lean
compiler
feedback
and
self
-summarization
to
improve
proofs.
Test
-time
scaling
employs
three
levels
of
strategies
based
on
inference
budgets
and
problem
difficulty.
This
figure
shows
an
example
of
whole
proof
and
lemma
-style
proof
in
lean
-for,
illustrating
the
structure
of
Seed
Prover's
approach.
Seed
Prover
employs
light,
medium,
and
heavy
inference
settings.
The
light
setting
refines
proofs
iteratively.
The
medium
setting
targets
difficult
lemmas
for
inner
refinement.
The
heavy
setting
uses
a
conjecture
pool
and
lemma
pool
to
explore
diverse
problem
properties.
Each
lemma
is
scored
based
on
its
proof
rate,
semantic
relevance,
and
proof
length.
This
diagram
illustrates
the
workflow
of
the
heavy
inference
setting,
showcasing
the
proposer,
light
inference,
and
medium
inference
stages.
Seed
Prover
and
Seed
Geometry
represent
significant
advancements
in
automated
theorem
proving.
By
integrating
large
language
models
with
formal
reasoning
frameworks,
these
systems
achieve
state
-of
-the
-art
performance.
The
use
of
formal
languages
like
Lean
enables
rapid
-proof
verification,
making
these
systems
more
cost
-effective
and
reliable.
work
will
focus
on
tackling
open
conjectures.
Thanks
for
watching.
Don't
forget
to
like
and
subscribe
for
more
deep
diveys
into
the
latest
research.